<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Institute for Datability Science, Osaka University</title><link>/project/</link><atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:13:28 +0900</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/large.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>/project/</link></image><item><title>Knowledge VQA</title><link>/project/kiban_b-kvqa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:13:28 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/kiban_b-kvqa/</guid><description>&lt;p>Visual question answering (VQA) with knowledge is a task that requires knowledge to answer questions on images/video. This additional requirement of knowledge poses an interesting challenge on top of the classic VQA tasks. Specifically, a system needs to explore external knowledge sources to answer the questions correctly, as well as understanding the visual content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We created
&lt;a href="https://knowit-vqa.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a dedicated dataset for our knowledge VQA task&lt;/a> and made it open to the public so that everyone can enjoy our new task. We have also published several papers on this task.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="publications">Publications&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Noa Garcia, Mayu Otani, Chenhui Chu, and Yuta Nakashima (2019). KnowIT VQA: Answering knowledge-based questions about videos. Proc. AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Feb. 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zekun Yang, Noa Garcia, Chenhui Chu, Mayu Otani, Yuta Nakashima, and Haruo Takemura (2020). BERT representations for video question answering. Proc. IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Noa Garcia, Chenhui Chu, Mayu Otani, and Yuta Nakashima (2019). Video meets knowledge in visual question answering. MIRU.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zekun Yang, Noa Garcia, Chenhui Chu, Mayu Otani, Yuta Nakashima, and Haruo Takemura (2019). Video question answering with BERT. MIRU.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Australian History in Newspaper and AI</title><link>/project/australian-history/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:13:06 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/australian-history/</guid><description>&lt;p>In collaboration with
&lt;a href="http://www.let.osaka-u.ac.jp/seiyousi/fujikawa.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Fujikawa&lt;/a> at Graduate School of Letters, Osaka University, we are working on exploring Australian history through public meetings, of which call for participation appears in newspapers from back then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We explore ways to analyze such newspapers with state-of-the-art technologies in NLP to make OCR output better and to automatically detect/structure call for participation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kiban_s Plenoptic</title><link>/project/kiban_s-plenoptic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:12:37 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/kiban_s-plenoptic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crest 3d Cancer</title><link>/project/crest-3d-cancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:08:48 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/crest-3d-cancer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Society 5.0 Projects</title><link>/project/society5_0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:07:15 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/society5_0/</guid><description>&lt;p>Institute for Datability Science, Osaka University is now working on
&lt;a href="http://www.ids.osaka-u.ac.jp/ildi/en/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Society 5.0&lt;/a> using information science and technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the world of Society 5.0, innovations in IoT, Big Data, robotics, and AI will be part of everyday life, helping people lead active and high-quality lives, creating a super-smart society. This project encourages collaboration across projects and university organizations, thus promoting faster adoption of research results in real-world society.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Under this big project, we are working two sub-projects:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="social-sensing-for-society-50">Social sensing for Society 5.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sensing technologies that aggregate various types of information from publicly and ubiquitously available social probes including social networking services are essential for providing various services in the world of Society 5.0. We are working towards establishing a social sensing technology that can infer emotional states of people for timely services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-school-technology-for-society-50">Future school technology for Society 5.0&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Education everywhere is one of SDGs, and e-learning is one solution toward this. We collectively working on a broad range of technologies related to e-learning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Esthetic Dentistry and Optical Analysis</title><link>/project/esthetic-dentistry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:06:58 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/esthetic-dentistry/</guid><description>&lt;p>There have been ever-increasing demands for esthetics in the oral cavity after tooth restorations. Especially in the anterior, functional restoration is not enough; restored teeth should have similar color tones and light transmissions to natural teeth because the appearance of restored teeth when exposed to light varies greatly depending on the material used for the crown restoration device and the abutment structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore, by analyzing the optical properties of various dental restoration materials and dental tissues via optical simulation, the behavior of light in natural teeth and dental restorations is visualized and analyzed for esthetic tooth restorations.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="/project/esthetic-dentistry/bs02_ja_hufa2c9813ab5ec072b2ff3aff4129a81c_207794_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="/project/esthetic-dentistry/bs02_ja_hufa2c9813ab5ec072b2ff3aff4129a81c_207794_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="654" height="272">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Brain Pharmaceutics</title><link>/project/brain-pharmaceutics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:06:11 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/brain-pharmaceutics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming soon&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AI Hospital</title><link>/project/ai-hospital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:05:12 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/ai-hospital/</guid><description>&lt;p>Osaka University Medical Hospital has launched
&lt;a href="https://www.hosp.med.osaka-u.ac.jp/english/departments/ai.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Artificical Intelligence Center for Medical Research and Application (AIM)&lt;/a>, which supports physicians, nurses, and all the medical staff collaborating with medical information specialists and data scientists to boost the medical application of AI in daily practices of the hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are collaborating with AIM to provide cutting-edge technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ophthalmology-and-ai">Ophthalmology and AI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In ophthalmology or any other departments, vessels in retinal fundus images provide rich information on the cardiovascular system of human bodies. We proposed a state-of-the-art method, coined
&lt;a href="publication/li-2020-a/">IterNet&lt;/a> for extracting vessels from retinal fundus images as in the (e) in the figure below.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="/project/ai-hospital/iternet_hu5ea4eead4f7a5d7e4e3c54a3ef2dbf33_96994_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg" >
&lt;img data-src="/project/ai-hospital/iternet_hu5ea4eead4f7a5d7e4e3c54a3ef2dbf33_96994_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg" class="lazyload" alt="" width="720" height="380">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>On top of this technology, we also invented a new method for classifying vessels into artery/vein, which takes a two-step approach: We firstly segment vessels in input images using an IterNet-based method and then classify them into artery/vein with some post-processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="/project/ai-hospital/segmentation_hu6603ce41fa995fbca303679a56d9cb90_58078_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg" >
&lt;img data-src="/project/ai-hospital/segmentation_hu6603ce41fa995fbca303679a56d9cb90_58078_2000x2000_fit_q90_lanczos.jpg" class="lazyload" alt="" width="720" height="371">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Law and AI</title><link>/project/green_law/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 23:02:32 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/green_law/</guid><description>&lt;p>In collaboration with
&lt;a href="https://researchmap.jp/read0180483?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Noriko Okubo&lt;/a> at Graduate School of Law and Politics, Osaka University, we are studying to automatically evaluate how green laws are enforced in different countries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Green laws&amp;rsquo; participation principle consists of 1) the information access right, 2) participation in the policy decision process, 3) the judicial access; however, actual implementation varies country to country, and legal methodologies have been explored for evaluating their effectiveness. This work investigates legal evaluation criteria on the green laws&amp;rsquo; participation principle, analyzes Japanese participation system&amp;rsquo;s pros and cons in a comparative perspective, and propose some recommendations to establish the environmental democracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The difficulty lies in how to automatically find out related legislations, cases, statutes, etc. in different languages. As the first attempt, we proposed a method for identifying the topic of such legal documents through analyzing citation networks in addition to classic topic modeling. The figure below shows citation networks among different types of legal documents (e.g., cases-prior cases).&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="/project/green_law/citation_networks_huab3f0c6cd7d27657c2614c3ccbddca1e_853493_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="/project/green_law/citation_networks_huab3f0c6cd7d27657c2614c3ccbddca1e_853493_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="1915" height="624">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Buddha Face and AI</title><link>/project/buddha-face/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 22:52:41 +0900</pubDate><guid>/project/buddha-face/</guid><description>&lt;p>In collaboration with
&lt;a href="http://www.dma.jim.osaka-u.ac.jp/view?l=en&amp;amp;u=6617" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Fujioka&lt;/a> with Graduate School of Letters/School of Letters, Osaka University, we are attempting to create an AI for analyzing various aspects of Buddha faces in images.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focusing on the face of the Buddha image, i.e., &amp;ldquo;Buddha face&amp;rdquo;, we analyze the characteristics of the style of each region, era, and author using statistical and machine learning approaches based on images and 3D geometric data, building a genealogy of Buddha faces. This is to realize style judgment based on the knowledge obtained from data, not based on the experience of art historians, which promotes the globalization of the Buddha statue research and also helps to identify the genealogy of Buddha faces propagated through the Silk Road, giving a new perspective on the spread of culture in Asia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have built several interfaces to browse through a large corpus of precious Buddha faces for facilitating annotations on the basic meta-data on the statues, which will then serve as a source to train more sophisticated models for analyzing them.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="/project/buddha-face/interfaces_hu412127b82145130d68f689675871a563_688796_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="/project/buddha-face/interfaces_hu412127b82145130d68f689675871a563_688796_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="1519" height="343">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>For example, we built a model that can embed various information on target entities (i.e., Buddha status), such as authors, eras, places, etc., into a vector representation of images and use them for other tasks like classification, through the model below.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="/project/buddha-face/contextnet_hu255c0008cb8fe6340d26b769ee3d244e_313842_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="/project/buddha-face/contextnet_hu255c0008cb8fe6340d26b769ee3d244e_313842_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="1358" height="600">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>